レオリオ！
Genthru and his men have a plan in mind, as they prepare to trade
with Team Tsezgerra. Let's get this over with, then.
ツチハブの群れに 出口をふさがれたゴン達
I cannot accept this. This is an unfair trade.
だが　蛇の群れを操るバーボンは すでに死んでいた
What? Don't complain once it's done! We gave you three cards! What more do you want?
罠を張った張本人が 死んでしまったというのか？
Wait a second...
That isn't what I meant.
なぜだ？ 私が　やったの。
I'm saying that it's unfair to you.
方法は企業秘密。
It's too skewed in our favor. I dislike the idea of
benefiting from charity.
ゴン　レオリオを頼む。 うん。 ん？
And it will continue to bother me, even if we clear the game first.
無駄よ。
Okay!
彼に触れるか この洞窟から出ようとする。 この　いずれかの条件を満たすと 蛇が　一斉に攻撃して来るようよ。
Levy on!
毒をもって毒を制すか。
To Masadora!
傷口から見て 凶器はシビレヤリバチだろう。
Let's go after them! Wait!
死因は恐らく アナフィラキシーショック。
First, check your cards!
アナフィラキシーショック？ うん。
I lost one of the #80 cards
we were monopolizing.
人間の体には 一度　蜂に刺されると
As well as a #65. Hey, what did you lose?
その蜂の毒に対する抗体が出来る。
I lost #42 and #53.
だが　抗体を持った人間が 再び　その蜂に刺されると
I lost #29 and #24. They got me good!
アレルギー反応を起こす。
I lost two of the #85
cards we were hoarding.
この反応が激しい状態を アナフィラキシーショックといって
All the ones they took were
restricted slot cards... And they took both card types
that we were monopolizing.
場合によっては 死に至ることがある。 参ったわ　ご名答よ。
Damn! They must have used Risky Dice.
じゃあ　君が蜂を使って…。
We're not with them!
バーボンは　私のターゲットなの。
They used items to change our faces!
入り口から催眠ガスを噴射。 頃合いを見て　中へ入った。
But he went like this with his hand and
blew the head off the guy I was with. A power clearly meant for murder.
この時すでに 彼は　罠を張ってたわけ。
They could have completed
their collection! List on! #2!
)
Currently, 0 players own #2, Patch of Shore.
Currently, 0 cards in play.
洞窟の奥深くの
We're still okay.
岩の割れ目に隠れていた 蛇の大部分には
They haven't found #2,
Patch of Shore, yet.
ガスが十分に 行きわたらなかったみたい。
Our immediate priority
まぁ　体に触れる前に 後ろに飛びのいたから
is to find #2 before they do!
蛇は噛みついて来なかったけど
We still have our voucher
for Breath of Archangel, so we can still beat them.
逆に　私の攻撃スイッチが 入っちゃったの。
Right, let's find it first, then.
あっ。 そんな所に蜂を！
To Soufrabi!
私が悲鳴をあげたり 倒れたりすると
We did it... A big success.
このコ達が 近くの人間に襲いかかるの。
The Risky Dice and Levy
combination paid off.
前に刺されたことがあるなんて 分かんないしさ。
No, we used one up to
change those faces, so it's ninety-two.
蛇達のせいで 手当ても　できないし。 まぁ　それは不可抗力だけど…。
The important thing is that we took
the cards they were monopolizing.
戻っていいよ。
And for two of the others, we're just
waiting for someone to use Gain on them.
問題は 罠を張った本人が死んでも
But we know that it's in Soufrabi.
蛇の攻撃スイッチが 解除されないってことよ。
All right, we'll go after #72, #21, and #9 in that order.
もう　解除方法を聞き出すことも 調べることもできない。
Then we'll make for
Soufrabi, to find #2.
うっ…　うぅ…。 レオリオ。
For #75, we simply need to find
someone with it, then take it.
はぁ…　私は　もう諦めた。
I think it's time we began thinking...
審査委員会が 助けに来てくれるのを待つわ。 審査委員会が？
About the three restricted
slot cards we want to keep, and how we want to spend the 50 billion.
この洞窟まで 助けに来るというのか。
Hey, Killua...
知らないの？
Something's been bugging me.
ナンバープレートには 発信機が仕込まれていて
Huh? Aren't there hundreds of players?
受験者の位置は チェックされてるのよ。
Isn't it weird that we've been able
期日を過ぎても 戻らない場合は 委員会が捜してくれるってわけ。
to turn all our items into cards? What do you mean?
もちろん　プレートをなくしたり 取られたらアウトだけど 幸い　期日は一日を切ってるし
Even B-rank restricted slot types
have a thirty-card limit.
今年は　諦めて 助けを待ったほうがいいわね。
The players here before us should
have already collected them.
そうは　いかない。 ん？
That's true. But you can also see it this way.
レオリオの症状は一刻を争う。 すぐに医者に診せなければ。
Fewer than thirty teams in this game
are capable of making real progress.
期日が来るまで 委員会は動いてくれないわ。
Oh, I see.
プレートをなくした者は 見捨てるくらいなのよ。
Most players aren't worried
about getting restricted slot cards.
そいつが悪いのよ 忠告したのに…。
They're just struggling to find
a way out of the game.
((クラピカ！　ゴン！ 来るな！　蛇だ！))
It would suck if you got to Masadora,
and there weren't any Leave cards.
)
Yeah, that's why...
救助が来るまで　彼の体力が もつことを祈るしかないわね。
I get it... Huh?
いや　まだ方法は　ある 成功する可能性も高い
If you guys got to Masadora,
but there weren't any Leave cards, what would you do? Well...
だが　もしも　あれがなかったら もう一人　犠牲者が出る
I'd save money until a Leave showed up. Yeah.
クラピカ。
Okay, then what if
レオリオを頼むよ。 ゴン？
you acquired a super rare
spell card while waiting?
あるよ　きっと！ ゴン…。
Sell it and buy more spell
cards until a Leave came in. Really?!
おい　ゴン！
I would save it...
ちょっと待って　何する気？ ひとの話　聞いてたの？ ねぇ！
Wouldn't it suck if all the cards you
bought ended up being worthless? If you saved it, you might be
able to trade for a Leave—
な…　何て子なの…。
Need a Leave?
は…　早く　レオリオに…。
Okay, that makes a total
of fifty-four types. Score!
さぁ　次はゴンだ。 うん。 信じられない。
Then we should organize them now. We three have a total
of 135 free pockets.
持ってるかどうかも分からない 解毒剤を探すために
We should each leave
around 5 pockets free.
毒蛇の中に…？
You keep the spell cards, Killua.
持っている可能性は　高かった。 えっ？
Bisky should also have
a few defensive ones.
相手に毒を盛る場合
Wait! I have to use spell cards?
解毒剤がなければ 駆け引きが成立しないからな。
No way! I don't know how they work. The hell? Then learn how they work!
それは…　そうかもしれないけど。
Okay...
それでも 毒蛇の群れに飛び込むのは 並の度胸じゃ　できないがな レオリオも　安定して来た。 もう　大丈夫だろう。 大した友情ね。
Book. We've been deliberately
avoiding other players, but we'll have to take risks
to obtain the rarer cards. Yeah.
う…　うぅ…　あっ。 ねぇ　催眠ガスって まだ残ってる？
Well, let's get what we can ourselves, then negotiate aggressively
with any players we come across.
あるけど。 これと　交換しない？
Sound good? Yeah. Yep!
あっ！　それは　バーボンの…。
See ya.
これがあれば 君も６点分　貯まるんでしょ？
Hold on.
ええ　そうよ。
This is worthless.
でも　催眠ガスと交換って どうするつもり？
It's a transformed Fake.
もちろん　蛇を全部　眠らせて ここから出るんだ。
Sorry about that.
I gave you the wrong one. Here's the real one.
確かに　催眠ガスは入り口から 噴射するより　格段に効くわよ。
Man, you can't lower your guard
around any of these guys.
５分もあれば　洞窟内に充満して 全ての蛇を 眠らせることもできるわ。
No kidding... Still, that necklace is quite useful.
でも５分よ？ その間　息を止めているなんて できっこないわ。 ガスを吸い込んで こっちまで眠っちゃったら
Hey, this necklace can
remove curses, right?
何の意昧も　ないじゃない。 ９分４４秒。
Only from spell cards. Oh, so it won't work.
えっ？ 俺の最高記録だよ。
Did you have an idea?
俺が息を止めて みんなを運び出す。
I was wondering if a curse
was behind the disease that all those villagers
were suffering from.
信用できないわ。
Villagers?
自分一人だけ 逃げ出すかもしれないじゃない。
Oh, those people...
そんな奴が レオリオを救うために
The ones who took all your money.
毒蛇の中へ 自分から飛び込むと思うか？
But it won't work since
they aren't cards.
信用して！ 必ず　君も　ここから連れ出す！
No. It's worth a shot.
うん。
Will you trust us with your lives?
準備ＯＫよ！ 俺が合図したらガスを噴射してね。 分かったわ。
You freely gave us everything you had.
はぁ…。
We will trust you!
１９９…　２００…　２０１…
Thank you very much!
２０２…　２０３…
This treasure has been
passed down for generations.
２０４…　２０５…
Please accept this
token of our gratitude.
２０６…　２０７…
Awesome! Lucky Alexandrite! Score!
ブハっ　よっしゃ！
Another player has used
Contact to reach you. Yo, this is Kazsule. I'd like to talk to you.
じゃあ　バーボンのプレートは 置いてくから
It's a team of three,
led by someone named Genthru.
委員会が見つけてくれるよね。
Genthru!
君のプレートがあれば
Thanks for coming, everyone.
レオリオも６点分になって 合格なんだ。 運賃ってことで　もらってくよ ごめんね！
Much appreciated. As I mentioned via Contact, Team Genthru is close
to completing the game. I just checked the ranking, and they're currently
at ninety-six types.
第４次試験は終了となります。
Can I ask something? What is it?
受験者の皆さんは　速やかに スタート地点まで　お戻りください。
How do you check the ranking? Well... You don't know how to do that?
これより１時間を 猶予時間とさせていただきます。
If we answer all their questions,
we'll be here till dawn!
それまでに戻られない場合
Just cut to the chase.
全て不合格と見なしますので ご注意ください。
Now, don't be so mean... We're all here to exchange information.
なお　スタート地点へ到着後の プレート交換は無効です。
They could have information
you don't, Asta.
確認され次第 失格となりますので
That's impossible.
ご注意ください。
Those kids are amateurs who don't even
know how to use the Trade Shop.
では　到着した人から プレートを確認します。
use Contact or Fluoroscopy on them. Not until you actually meet them.
４４番　ヒソカさん。
Don't you feel smarter now, boys?
５３番　ポックルさん。 ９９番　キルアさん。 ３０１番　ギタラクルさん。
In other words, if we know
the members of a team, we can determine how
many cards they have.
１９１番　ボドロさん。 ２９４番　ハンゾーさん。
And Team Genthru is only missing #0, #2, #9, and #75. #75...
…と　合格者は　この６名かな？
There's a solid theory that #0 appears
あら？ おっ？
in an event after the other
ninety-nine are collected, so they only need three.
ゴン！ おっと　さらに３人
We propose to find one of those
three types before they do
駆け込みセーフです！ キルア。
and monopolize it, to prevent
them from clearing the game.
フッ。
We could deluge them with spell cards.
はい　ラスト！　まずは
They already have a Paladin's Necklace. So Levy is the only
spell that will work.
４０４番　クラピカさん！
And they can block Levy if
certain conditions are met.
４０３番　レオリオさん！
It's safe to assume
そして ４０５番　ゴンさんです！
that Genthru is willing to reveal
that they have ninety-six types
以上　９名の方が
because their pages are
protected by Prison.
第４次試験　合格者です！
That's possible...
ホッホッホ…
Genthru was collecting
a bunch of spell cards with the others who tried to recruit us.
９人中６人がルーキーか！
It's a reasonable assumption.
豊作　豊作！
We could always take
their cards by force.
こんなことって 前にもあったんですか？
Would you be willing to lead the attack?
うむ　大概　前触れがあって
We don't know what kind
of abilities they have.
１０年くらい　ルーキーの合格者が 一人も出ない時が続く。
Finding a card type to monopolize
is the most practical option.
そして突然 わっと有望な若者が集まりよる。
I assume no one has objections.
わしが会長になって これで４度目かのぉ。
Then let's get to business. We'll need everyone here to cooperate.
ところで　最終試験は 一体　何をするのでしょう？
I'm fine with the proposed plan. But I have a problem with these members.
あっ　そうそう！　まだ　僕らも 聞いてなかったですよ！
Hold on, Asta. I followed your condition...
うむ　それだが
Have over fifty types of cards.
いっぷう変わった 決闘をしてもらうつもりじゃ。
These six teams met that condition.
ん？　いっぷう変わった決闘？
I also said that they had to be
people who could contribute.
まず９人　それぞれと 話がしたいのぉ。
I don't see how these kids
can contribute anything.
情けねえ話だが　４次試験は
You're the one being uncooperative. You've got a smart mouth.
完全に　お前ら２人の 世話になっちまった。
Then show me some proof
that you can be useful.
借りは　必ず返すからよ。
We know Team Genthru's abilities.
その…　あ…　ありがとな。
We have one of the three
cards they're missing.
これより　会長が面談を行います。 面談？
No, that's good enough. So tell us what their abilities are.
２階の第１応接室へ お越しください。 では　受験番号４４番 ヒソカ様から
Show us some proof you
can be useful to us.
よろしくお願いいたします。
We have seventy-one types
of restricted slot cards... Significantly more than you.
まぁ　座りなされ。
I'll give you an A-rank card in
return for the information. You shouldn't have a problem with that.
まさか　これが最終試験かい？
I have a problem.
全く関係ないとは言わんが
We can obtain A-rank cards ourselves.
まぁ　参考までに　ちょいと 質問する程度のことじゃよ。
So give us two S-rank cards or
equally valuable information. Otherwise, we won't tell you a thing.
ふん。
Don't get too cocky, brat! Did you hear that, everyone?
まず　なぜ ハンターに　なりたいのかな？
They want two S-rank
cards from each team. That's ten cards they'd take.
「けど」？
I'm only taking cards from your team.
資格を持ってると いろいろ便利だから。
Huh? I'm fine with giving information
to the other four.
ほぉ　例えば？ 例えば
I'll let them decide
what to offer in return.
人を殺しても 免責になる場合が多いしね。
But I won't tell you anything
until you meet my condition.
なるほど　では　次の質問じゃ。
You are a stupid brat... Throwing a tantrum because
I didn't baby you, huh?
おぬし以外の８人の中で 一番注目しているのは？
Stop this, both of you... We don't have time to
fight amongst ourselves! I haven't agreed to
team up with them yet!
９９番。
It's fine, Asta...
ほぉ。
Give them two cards.
４０５番も捨て難いけど 一番は　彼だね。
We need to move on. What?! I have no problem with
giving them cards!
いつか　手合わせ願いたいな フッフフフ…。
But that kid's trying to pick a fight! You're the one picking a fight!
うむ　では最後の質問じゃ。
Hey, let's leave.
８人の中で 今　一番戦いたくないのは？
I don't want to team
up with these people! Come, now...
Though I admit I'm a bit peeved.
それは４０５番だね。
But given the circumstances...
９９番もそうだが。 ほぉ。 今は　まだ戦いたくない …という意味では ４０５番が一番かな。
Genthru has these two abilities,
Countdown and Little Flower.
うむ　なるほど。
So it's best to keep
your distance from him.
ちなみに　今 一番戦ってみたいのは
Seriously? He got me... Same here. He touched me when we
were making a deal.
あんたなんだけどね。
Me, too...
うむ　ご苦労じゃった。
Sounds like a bunch of
them might be victims. A chance!
下がってよいぞ。
Isn't there any way to
disable his technique?
食えない　じいさんだな
You have to touch Genthru and say,
"I caught the Bomber." Stupid! Why did you tell them?
まるで隙だらけで 毒気　抜かれちゃったよ
We could've gotten more
cards out of them! That would have started another fight. The bombs can't be armed until Genthru
explains how his ability works, so if you keep away from him, you should be safe.
見る限り　一番バランスがいい。 戦いたくないのは…　４４番。
Did you know there are
two ways to cast spells? Yep, I did.
正直　戦闘では　かなわないだろう。
A spell card is used up the
moment you say its name aloud.
ゴンだね　同い年だし。
But it's possible to
keep reusing a spell.
戦いたくないのは　５３番かなぁ。
Huh? For example, you know how a list
戦っても　面白そうじゃないし。
of players you've met appears if
you put Steal in your binder?
注目しているのは ４４番だな　イヤでも目につく。 ４０５番と９９番は　まだ子供だ。
If you remove the card without
pressing the select button, the spell card isn't used up,
so you can keep reusing it.
戦うなど考えられぬ。
I never tried that. Yeah.
カタカタカタ… ９９番。
You can buy all B-rank
restricted slot cards at stores.
４４番。
You simply need to buy from the
same Trade Shop over fifty times.
注目してる人？ ４４番のヒソカ。
If you become a frequent customer,
they'll start making you offers.
いろいろあって　気になってる。
Do you have two Skeleton Glasses cards?
９９番　４０３番
Or Emerald for Beauty and Mystery Pond?
４０４番の３人は　選べないや。
Is that enough information to satisfy you?
４４番だな。
I'll give you another
card if you're not happy.
こいつが　とにかく 一番ヤバいしな。
Nope, that's enough, thanks!
戦いたくない相手は もちろん４４番だ。
I'm up next, then. I'm Goreinu. Nice to meet you.
注目しているのは いい意味で４０５番。
Thanks, everyone!
悪い意味で４４番。
That was very educational.
理由があれば　誰とでも戦うし
The question now is which card
we should try to monopolize.
なければ　誰とも争いたくはない。
It's probably impossible to
monopolize the #75 we have.
４０５番だな　恩もあるし。 合格してほしいと思うぜ。
Each team can only obtain one,
and the limit is twenty, which is too high.
そんなわけで ４０５番とは戦いたくねえな。
You obtained #75? That's impressive.
うん　思ったより偏ったのぉ。
List on! #75. Currently, 6 players own #75, Lucky Alexandrite.
Currently, 6 cards are in play.
ゴン。
What about the other two? List on!
いよいよ　最終試験だな。
#9! List on.
うん。
#2.
うむ！　これで　よし！
No one has #2, Patch of Shore...
待たせたのぉ！ 組み合わせが出来たぞえ。
I know where to find it... Soufrabi. I've been there before!
えっ？ これは？
I have an Accompany card here. Okay, let's go.
か…　会長！
Accompany on! To Soufrabi!
ヘッヘッヘ…　大マジじゃ。
This is Soufrabi?
確かに　本気の目ですな。
It's a pretty big city...
本気の目なんだ…　あれ。
Let's head in and snoop around.
これで勝てば 晴れてハンターの仲間入りじゃ。
Search every room, one by one.
ゴン。 ん？
until you visit multiple
times, so pay attention. Okay! Hey!
４次試験中に　何かあったのか？
I found someone with information. Fast!
合流した時に 様子が少し　おかしかったのが 気になってな。
The pirates rule this city... There's a legend about
an underwater cavern
ゼビル島を出てからも 気持が ふさいでいるように見える。
called the Sea God's Grotto
located somewhere in this area.
俺のターゲット… ヒソカだったんだ。
Patch of Shore is the entrance to it.
隙を見て　一度は プレートを奪ったんだけど 俺も　他の奴に　つけられてて 毒矢にやられたんだ。
A few years ago, having heard of the
legendary cavern and its treasure, fifteen pirates arrived in this city.
結局　その後　ヒソカが　そいつから 奪い返した自分のプレートを 俺に置いてったんだ。
Razor and the fourteen devils... The city fishermen were
all tortured and killed.
「貸しだ」とか言って。 ヒソカが？ 「いらない」って言ったら ぶっ飛ばされて…。
The pirates murdered anyone who
knew about Patch of Shore. If you get rid of the pirates,
I'll tell you what I know.
((今みたいに 僕の顔に　１発ぶち込むことが できたら受け取ろう))
When we visited a few months earlier,
we couldn't find a single clue.
すごく…　悔しくて悔しくて…。
Maybe an event that only
occurs at this time frame? Razor and the fourteen devils...
そしたら　その後 無性に情けなくて寂しくなってさ。
But how would a game
character know that? Oh, Accompany!
あんまりにも　自分の力が 不足してるような気がして。
Yes, a group of fifteen or more must
reach Soufrabi with Accompany.
だから　誰かのそばにいて
That's probably the
trigger for this event.
誰かの 役に立ちたくなった…　のかな。
Brutal... Huh? Oh, nothing.
それで　２人を捜し回ってたんだ。
Let's go to the pirate's base!
俺のほうこそ　ありがとう。
Gon and his friends stand before
some unpleasant looking pirates. Will the fifteen allies be able
to obtain Patch of Shore?